const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",o="chemistry",t=200,i=120,a=[{id:193,question:"Equal moles of ethyne and hydrogen iodide react to give",option:{a:"CH2 = CH2",b:"CH2 = CHI",c:"CH2 – CHI",d:"CH2 – CI3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:20,question:"Which of the following best explains the increase in the rate of a chemical reaction as the temperature rises",option:{a:"The bonds in the reacting molecules are more readily broken",b:"The molecules collisions become more violent",c:"A lower proportion of the molecules has the necessary minimum energy to react",d:"The collision frequency of the molecules increases"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:92,question:"Farmlands affected by crude –oil spillage can be decontaminated by",option:{a:"Adding acidic solutions",b:"Using aerobic bacteria",c:"Pouring water on the affected area",d:"Burning off the oil from the area"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:139,question:"Calcium Tetraoxosulphate(VI) dissolves in water only sparingly to form a",option:{a:"Solution",b:"Suspension",c:"Precipitate",d:"Colloid"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:264,question:"The volume of a gas is Vcm3 at P mm Hg. What is the new volume of the gas if the pressure is reduced to half at constant temperature",option:{a:"2 V cm3",b:"V  2cm3",c:"V cm3",d:"4 V cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:252,question:"Carbon exists naturally in the combined state as",option:{a:"Diamond",b:"Coal",c:"Wood",d:"Graphite"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:148,question:"Which of the following hydrogen halides has the highest entropy value",option:{a:"HF",b:"HCl",c:"HBr",d:"Hl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:4,question:"Cancerous growths are cured by exposure to",option:{a:"ɣ-rays",b:" β – rays",c:" ἀ – rays",d:"X -rays"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:134,question:"Which of the following mixtures of gases is likely to burn in flame",option:{a:"Neon and hydrogen",b:"Nitrogen and helium",c:"Helium and neon",d:"Neon and nitrogen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:163,question:"A characteristic of the alkane family is",option:{a:"Addition reaction",b:"Elimination reaction",c:"Substitution reaction",d:"Neutralization reaction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:179,question:"NH4CI(g) ⇌   NH3(g)  +  HCI(g)   The reaction above can only attain equilibrium if",option:{a:"It is in a closed system",b:"It is in an open system",c:"One of the products is removed",d:"A gaseous reactant is added"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:234,question:"A degree in atomic size and an increase in knuckler charge across a period lead to",option:{a:"A decrease in covalency in bond formation",b:"An increase in chemical reactivity",c:"An increase in the tendency to loss electrons",d:"A decrease in electro positivity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:48,question:"A little quantity of Trichloromethane (b.pt.600C) was added to a large quantity of ethanol (b.pt.780C). the most probable boiling point of the resultant mixture is from",option:{a:"699C – 700C",b:"820C – 840C",c:"600C – 780C",d:"700C – 744C"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:80,question:"Neutral atoms of neon with atomic number 10 have the same number of electrons as",option:{a:"O2+",b:"Ca2+",c:"K+",d:"Mg2+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:298,question:"Which of the following is used to hasten the ripening of fruit",option:{a:"Ethanol",b:"Ethyne",c:"Ethane",d:"Ethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:142,question:"The oxidation state of chlorine in HClO4 is",option:{a:"-5",b:"-1",c:"1",d:"7"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:29,question:"NH3(g)  +  HCI(g)  → NH4CI(s) The entropy change in the system is",option:{a:"Negative",b:"Indeterminate",c:"Positive",d:"Zero"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:130,question:"An electron can be added to a halogen atom to form a halide ion with",option:{a:"2 valence electrons",b:"3 valence electrons",c:"7 valence electrons",d:"Valence electrons"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:168,question:"In the production of soap, concentrated sodium chloride solution is added to",option:{a:"Increase the solubility of the soap",b:"Decrease the solubility of the soap",c:"Saponify the soap",d:"Emulsify the soap"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:152,question:"Which of the following gases can be collected by the method of downward delivery",option:{a:"Chlorine",b:"Oxygen",c:"Ammonia",d:"Hydrogen"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:173,question:"Which of the following alloys contain iron",option:{a:"Steel and permalloy",b:"Duralumlin and steel",c:"nd Soft Solder a Duralumlin ",d:"Brass and bronze"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:2,question:"What mass of water is produced when 8.0g of hydriogen reacts with excess oxygen [H = 1, O = 16]",option:{a:"36.0g",b:"8.0g",c:"72.0g",d:"16.0g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:287,question:"2H2(g) +    O2(g)  ⇌ 2H2O(g)    ΔH   =  - ve  What happens to the equilibrium constant of the reaction above if the temperature is increased?",option:{a:"It becomes zero",b:"It decreases",c:"It increases",d:"It is unaffected"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:227,question:"The order in which a mixture of sand ammonium chloride and sodium chloride can be separated is",option:{a:"Sublimation   dissolution  filtration  evaporation",b:"Dissolution  dryness  filtration  evaporation",c:"Filtration  sublimation  evaporation  dryness",d:"Dissolution  filtration  sublimation  evaporation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:137,question:"A carcinogenic substance is",option:{a:"Asbestos dust",b:"Sawdust",c:"Nitrogen(II) oxide",d:"Carbon (II) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:93,question:"When 10g of sodium hydroxide is dissolved in 1000cm3 of water, the solution formed is approximately   [Na = 23, H = 1, O = 16]",option:{a:"0.01 mol dm-3",b:"0.10 mol dm-3",c:"0.25 mol dm-3",d:"0.50 mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:49,question:"The chromatographic separation of ink is based on the ability of the components to",option:{a:"React with each other",b:"React with the solvent",c:"Dissolve in each other in the column",d:"Move at different speeds in the column"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:8,question:"An element X with relative atomic mass 16.2 contains two isotopes      X  with relative abundance of 90% and      X with relative abundance of 10%. The value of m is",option:{a:"16",b:"18",c:"12",d:"14"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:183,question:"What is the valence shell electron configuration of the element with atomic number 17",option:{a:"1s22s22p63s23p5",b:"1s22s22p63s23p4",c:"3s23p5",d:"2s22p6"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:117,question:"The type of reaction that is peculiar to benzene is",option:{a:"Addition",b:"Hydrolysis",c:"Polymerization",d:"Substitution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:199,question:"The enzyme responsible for converting sucrose into two simple isomeric sugars is",option:{a:"Invertase",b:"Amylase",c:"Lactose",d:"Maltase"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:268,question:"The maximum number of electrons in the L shell of an atom is",option:{a:"8",b:"18",c:"32",d:"2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:12,question:"Pure solvents are obtained by",option:{a:"Distillation",b:"Condensation",c:"Extraction",d:"EvapopraTION"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:51,question:"Which of the following solutions containing only hydroxyl ions will liberate hydrogen gas when reacted with magnesium metal",option:{a:"1.0 x 10-2 mol dm-3",b:"1.0 x 10-4 mol dm -3",c:"1.0 x 10-5 mol dm-3",d:"1.0 x 10-12 mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:101,question:` CO(g) + H2O(g) ⇌  CO2(g)  +  H2(g)
From the reaction above, calculate the standard heat change if the standard enthalpies of formation of CO2 (g), H2O (g) and CO (g) in kJ mol-1 are -394, -242 and -110 respectively.
`,option:{a:"-262 kJ  mol-1",b:"-42kJ mol-1",c:"+42 kJ mol-1",d:"+262 kJ mol-1"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:240,question:"CH3-CH2-C = CH  The hybridization in the compound above is",option:{a:"Sp3 and sp",b:"Sp3 and sp2",c:"Sp",d:"Sp2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:23,question:"C(s) + 2S (g)  → CS2 (g)      Δ H = +89kJ mol-1. The chemical equation above implies that",option:{a:"Each of carbon and sulphur has 89kJ of energy",b:"Both carbon and sulphur contribute 89kJ of energy",c:"89kJ of energy is released",d:"89kJ is absorbed"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:265,question:"Moving from left to right across a period, the general rise in the first ionization energy can be attributed to the",option:{a:"Increase in nuclear charge",b:"Decrease in screening effect",c:"Increase in screening effect",d:"Decrease in nuclear charge"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:71,question:"Which of the following gives a precipitate when treated with NaOH solution",option:{a:"Na2CO3",b:"CH3COONa",c:"NH4Cl",d:"AlCl3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:97,question:"Which of the following will change when a catalyst is added to a chemical reaction",option:{a:"The activation energy",b:"The potential energy of the reactants",c:"The heat of reaction",d:"The potential energy of the products"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:197,question:"A substance that is used as a ripening agent for fruits is",option:{a:"Propene",b:"Methane",c:"Ethene",d:"Butane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:68,question:"A rock sample was added to cold dilute HNMO3. The gas evolved was passed into a solution of acidified K2Cr2O7 and the solution turned green. The rock sample contains",option:{a:"NO3-",b:"Cl-",c:"SO42-",d:"SO32-"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:140,question:"Which of these compounds is a normal salt",option:{a:"NaHS",b:"NaSO4",c:"NaHCO3",d:"Na2CO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:98,question:"If Y is an oxidizing agent that reacts with a reducing agent, Z, which of the following is correct",option:{a:"Y increases in oxidation number",b:"Y becomes reduced",c:"Z loses protons",d:"Z gains protons"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:143,question:"ZnO(s) + CO (g) → Zn(s) + CO2 (g). ",option:{a:"Decomposed",b:"Displaced",c:"Oxidized",d:"Reduced"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:185,question:"The density of a certain gas is 1.98g dm-3 at s.t.p. What is the molecular mass of the gas   [Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4dm-3]",option:{a:"26.0g",b:"31.0g",c:"54.0g",d:"44.0g"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:190,question:"Which of these properties gives a solid its definite shape",option:{a:"Weak intermolecular attraction",b:"High boiling point",c:"High melting point",d:"Strong intermolecular attraction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:28,question:"In which of the following reactions has the oxidation number of nitrogen increased",option:{a:"2NO(g)  +  Br2(l)  → 2NOBr(l)",b:"2NO2(g)  +  O2(g)   → 2NO2(g)",c:"FeSO4(aq)  +  NO(g) → Fe(NO)SO4(s)",d:"2NO(g)  +  CI2(g) →  2NOCI(l)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:302,question:"The haloalkanes used in the dry cleaning industries are",option:{a:"Chloroethane and dichloroethene",b:"trichloroethene and tetrachloroethene",c:"chloromethane and dichloroethene",d:"Trichloromethane and tetrachloromethane"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:167,question:` Alkanol + Alkanoic acid ⇌  Ester + water.
The reverse reaction of the equation above is known as
`,option:{a:"Hydrolysis",b:"Saponification",c:"Hydration",d:"Fermentation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:261,question:"Which of the following is an example of a mixture",option:{a:"Blood",b:"Sand",c:"Washing soda",d:"Common salt"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:238,question:"An example of aliphatic unsaturated hydrocarbon is",option:{a:"Butanol",b:"Propene",c:"Pentane",d:"Benzene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:171,question:"A dense white fume is formed when ammonia gas reacts with",option:{a:"H2(g)",b:"O2(g)",c:"HCI(g)",d:"Cl2(g)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:204,question:"The air around smelting industries is likely to contain",option:{a:"CO2, SO3 and H2",b:"SO2N2 and CO2",c:"H2, SO2 and CO2",d:"H2S, CO and N2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:159,question:"Sodium metal is always kept under oil because it",option:{a:"Readily reacts with water",b:"Is reduced by atmospheric nitrogen",c:"Reacts vigorously on exposure to air",d:"Reacts with oxygen and carbon(IV) oxide"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:192,question:"Sugar is separated from its impurities by",option:{a:"Distillation",b:"Evaporation",c:"Precipitation",d:"Crystallization"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:274,question:"Coffee stains can best be removed by",option:{a:"Turpentine",b:"A solution of borax in water",c:"Ammonia solution",d:"Kerosene"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:280,question:"6AgNO3(aq)  +  PH3(g) +    3H2O(l)      →    6Ag(s)+   H3PO3(aq)   +    6HNO3(aq)  In the reaction above, the reducing agent is",option:{a:"H2O(l)",b:"PH3(g)",c:"AgNO3(aq)",d:"HNO3(AQ)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:246,question:"Which of the following results in the fall of acid rain",option:{a:"Gaseous hydrocarbons",b:"Oxide of lead",c:"Particulate matter",d:"Oxides of sulphur"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:42,question:"Which of the following metals burns brick with a brick-red",option:{a:"Pb",b:"Ca",c:"Na",d:"Ma"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:271,question:"Permanent hardness of water can be removed by",option:{a:"Adding slaked lime",b:"Adding caustic soda",c:"Boiling",d:"Filtration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:24,question:" 2SO2(g) + O2(g) ⇌  2SO3(g)  The equilibrium constant for the reaction above is increased by  [ΔH = -189kJ mol -1]",option:{a:"Increasing the temperature of the system",b:"Increasing the pressure of the system",c:"The addition of a catalyst to the system",d:"Increasing the surface area of the vessel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:9,question:"Which of the following statements is correct about the average kinetic energy of the molecules of a gas",option:{a:"It inctreasaes with increase in pressure",b:"It increases at constant pressure",c:"It increases with increase in temperature",d:"It increases in volume"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:54,question:"The furring of kettles is caused by the presence in water of",option:{a:"Calcium trioxocarbonate(IV)",b:"Calcium tetraoxosulphate(VI)",c:"CALCIUM HYDROXIDE",d:"Calcium hydrofentrioxocarbonate(IV)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:232,question:"The element with the electron configuration 1s22s22p3 is",option:{a:"Oxygen",b:"Chlorine",c:"Nitrogen",d:"Calcium"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:102,question:"When sugar is dissolved in tea, the reaction is always accompanied by",option:{a:"Positive entropy change",b:"Negative entropy change",c:"No entropy change",d:"A minimum entropy change"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:58,question:"The solubility of a salt of molar mass 101g at 200C is 0.34mol dm-3. If 3.40g of the salt is dissolved completely in 250cm3 of water in a beaker, the resulting solution is",option:{a:"Unsaturated",b:"A suspension",c:"Saturated",d:"Supersaturated"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:34,question:"Catalytic hydrogenation of benzene produces",option:{a:"Oil",b:"Cyclohexane",c:"Cycloexane",d:"Margarine"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:13,question:"What is the decrease in volume of air when pyrogallol is shaken with 30.00cm3 of air",option:{a:"15.00cm3",b:"6.00cm3",c:"0.63cm3",d:"0.06cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:43,question:"Which of the followinig respresents hybridization in ethyne?",option:{a:"Sp2",b:"Sp2d",c:"Sp3",d:"sp"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:38,question:"A characteristic reaction of the compounds with the general formula CnH2n is",option:{a:"Esterification",b:"Polymerization",c:"Decarboxylation",d:"Substitution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:45,question:"Which of the following gases contains the least number of atoms at s.t.p",option:{a:"4 moles of chlorine",b:"3 moles of ozone",c:"1 mole of butane",d:"7 moles of argon"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:254,question:"The efficiency of a solid catalyst to increase reaction rates depends on its",option:{a:"Concentration",b:"Solubility",c:"Quantity",d:"Surface area"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:50,question:"Steam changes the colour of anhydrous cobalt(II) chloride from",option:{a:"White to red",b:"Blue to white",c:"White to green",d:"Blue to pink"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:112,question:"Ethene reacts with hydrogen bromide to give",option:{a:"CH2Br2",b:"CH3CH2Br",c:"C2H2Br2",d:"CHBr3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:70,question:"The most important use of hydrogen is in the",option:{a:"Hydrogenation of oils",b:"Manufacture of methyl alcohol",c:"Manufacture of ammonia",d:"Manufacture of ethyl alcohol"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:289,question:"Which of the following is used as a rocket fuel",option:{a:"CH3COOH",b:"H2SO4",c:"HCL",d:"HNO3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:295,question:"Which of the following is used as fuel in miners’ lamp",option:{a:"Ethyne",b:"Ethane",c:"Ethane",d:"Ethanol"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:53,question:"The property which makes alcohol soluble in water is the",option:{a:"Hydrogen bonding",b:"Covalent nature",c:"Ionic character",d:"Boiling point"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:184,question:"A heterogeneous mixture can be defined as any mixture",option:{a:"Whose composition is uniform",b:"Whose composition is not uniform",c:"Formed by solids and liquids",d:"Of a solute and a solvent"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:111,question:"The modern process of manufacturing steel from iron is by",option:{a:"Treatment with acids",b:"Oxidation",c:"Blast reduction",d:"Treatment with alkalis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:223,question:"IN which of the following is the oxidation number of sulphur equal to -2",option:{a:"H2S",b:"SO3",c:"S8",d:"SO2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:292,question:"A compound gives an orange red colour to a non luminous flame. This compound is likely to contain",option:{a:"Ca2+",b:"Fe3+",c:"Fe2+",d:"Na+"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:257,question:"Group IA metals are not found free in nature because they",option:{a:"Have high melting and boiling points",b:"Conduct heat and electricity",c:"Are very reactive and unstable",d:"Are malleable and ductile"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:161,question:"The alkyl group can be represented by the general formula",option:{a:"CnH2n+1",b:"CnH2n",c:"CnH2n+2",d:"CnH2n-2"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:75,question:"What volume of oxygen is produced from the decomposition of 2 moles of KClO3 at s.t.p   [Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4 dm3]",option:{a:"22.4 dm3",b:"33.6 dm3",c:"44.8 dm3",d:"67.2 dm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:262,question:"Calculate the percentage by mass of nitrogen in calcium trioxonitrate (V)   {Ca = 40, N = 14, O = 16}",option:{a:"13.10%",b:"17.10%",c:"27.60%",d:"8.5"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:149,question:" N2O4(g)    ⇌  2NO2(g)",option:{a:"A constant volume",b:"An increase in pressure",c:"A decrease in pressure",d:" A decrease in volume"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:94,question:"A charge in the temperature of a saturated solution disturbs the equilibrium between the",option:{a:"Dissolved solute and the solvent",b:"Solvent and the undissolved solute",c:"Dissolved solute and the undissolved solute",d:"Dissolved solute and the solution"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:126,question:"What volume of gas is evolved at s.t.p. if 2g of calcium trioxocarbonate(IV) is added to a solution of hydrochloric acid    [Ca = 40, C = 12, O = 16, CI = 35.5, H = 1, Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p = 22.4dm3]",option:{a:"112cm3",b:"224cm3",c:"448cm3",d:"224cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:55,question:"Tetraoxosulphate(VI) acid burns the skin by",option:{a:"Heating",b:"Hydration",c:"Dehydration",d:"Hydrolysis"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:296,question:"Which of the following organic compounds is very soluble in water",option:{a:"C2H2",b:"C2H4",c:"CH3COOC2H5",d:"CH3COOH"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:35,question:"A trihydric alkanol is",option:{a:"glycerol",b:"phenol",c:"glycol",d:"ethanol"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:224,question:"5SO2(g)  +  2KMnO4(aq)  +  2H2O(l)  ⇌   K2SO4(aq)  +  2MnSO4(aq)  +   2H2HSO4(aq)   In the reaction above, the products give a",option:{a:"Colourless solution",b:"Purple precipitate",c:"Purple solution",d:"Colourless precipitate"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:255,question:"In the industrial production of H2 from natural gas, the CO2 produced along with the H2 is removed by",option:{a:"Passing the mixture into lime water",b:"Washing under pressure",c:"Drying over phosphorous(V)oxide",d:"Using ammoniac copper(l) chloride"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:155,question:"Carbon is tetravalent because",option:{a:"The electrons in both the 2s and 2p orbitals are equivalent",b:"The electrons in all the orbitals of carbon are equivalent",c:"The 2s and 2p atomic orbitals hybridize",d:"All the atomic orbitals of carbon hybridize"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:219,question:"Zinc and carbon rods are used as anode and cathode respectively in a",option:{a:"Voltaic cell",b:"Lead accumulator",c:"Leclanche cell",d:"Daniel cell"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:191,question:"The component of an atom that contributes least to its mass is the",option:{a:"Nucleus",b:"Neutron",c:"Electron",d:"Proton"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:108,question:"The salt that will form a precipitate soluble in excess ammonia solution is",option:{a:"Ca(NO3)2",b:"Cu(NO3)2",c:"Mg(NO3)2",d:"Al(NO3)3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:131,question:"The shape of the s-orbital is",option:{a:"Spherical",b:"Elliptical",c:"Spiral",d:"Circular"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:83,question:` I.  H = 1s1
II. O = 1s22s22p4
III. N = 1s22s22p3
IV. Zn = 1s22s22p63s23p64s23d10
From the above, which of the following pairs is likely to be paramagnetic?
`,option:{a:"I and II",b:"I and  III",c:"I    and IV",d:"III  and IV"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:220,question:"Trioxonitrate(V) acid is not used for preparing hydrogen gas from metals because it",option:{a:"Renders the metal passive",b:"Is strongly oxidizing",c:"Is volatile",d:""},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:65,question:"A fixed mass of gas has a  volume of 92cm3 at 30C. What will be be its volume at 180C if the pressure remains constant",option:{a:"15.3cm3",b:"87.3cm3",c:"97.0cm3",d:"552.0cm3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:121,question:"Which of the following is found in cotton",option:{a:"Starch",b:"Cellulose",c:"fat",d:"oil"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:95,question:"If an equilibrium reaction has   H>0, the reaction will proceed favourably in the forward direction at",option:{a:"High temperature",b:"Any temperature",c:"Low temperature",d:"Minimum temperature"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:60,question:"which of the following chlorides would exhibit the least ionic character",option:{a:"AlCl3",b:"CaCl2",c:"MgCi2",d:"LiCl"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:229,question:"[Molar volume of a gas at s.t.p + 22.4dm3} Nuclear fission involves the splitting of a heavy element into two nuclei of",option:{a:"Equal masses with a release of energy",b:"Nearly equal masses with a release of energy and radiation",c:"Equal masses with a release of energy and radiation",d:"Unequal masses without any release of energy"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:157,question:"Alloys are best prepared by",option:{a:"Electroplating",b:"Arc-welding",c:"Reducing a mixture of their metallic oxides",d:"Cooling a molten mixture of the metals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:276,question:"The acid that is used to remove rust is",option:{a:"Hydrochloric",b:"Trioxonitrate (V)",c:"Tetraoxosulphate (VI)",d:"Boric"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:187,question:"An element will readily form an electrovalent compound if its electron configuration is",option:{a:"2,8,8",b:"2,,8,4",c:"2,8,5",d:"2,8,1"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:110,question:"Chlorine gas turns a damp starch-iodide paper",option:{a:"Pink",b:"Colourless",c:"Red",d:"Dark blue"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:99,question:"When at equilibrium, which of the reactions below will shift to the right if the pressure is increased and the temperature is kept constant",option:{a:" 2SO3(g)  ⇌  2SO2(g)  +  O2(g)",b:" 2CO2(g)  ⇌ 2CO(g)  +  O2(g)",c:" 2H2(g)  +  O2(g) ⇌  2H2O(g)",d:" 2NO(g)   ⇌ N2(g)  +  O2(g)"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:194,question:"How many hydrogen atoms does a single ring cycloalkane have less than the corresponding open- chain alkane",option:{a:"Three",b:"One",c:"Four",d:"Two"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:7,question:"Four elements W, X, Y, and Z have atomic numbers 2, 6, 16 and 20 respectively. Which of these elements is a metal",option:{a:"X",b:"W",c:"Z",d:"Y"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:241,question:"Nigerian crude oil is described as light crude because of its",option:{a:"Low aliphatic hydrocarbon content",b:"Low sulphur content",c:"High natural gas content",d:"High octane number"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:273,question:"Calculate the solubility in mol dm -3 of 40g of Cu So4 dissolved in 100g of water at 1200C  {Cu = 64, S = 32, 0 = 16}",option:{a:"2.5",b:"0.4",c:"0.25",d:"4"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:245,question:"When 5.0cm3 of a saturated solution of sugar of molar mass 342g at 400C was evaporated to dryness, 34.2g of dry solid was obtained. The solubility of sugar at 400C is",option:{a:"7.0 mol dm-3",b:"3.5 mol dm-3",c:"2.0 mol dm-3",d:"10.0mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:178,question:"The most suitable metal that can be used as a lightening  conductor is",option:{a:"Aluminium",b:"Iron",c:"Copper",d:"Silver"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:59,question:"25cm3 of a 0.2mol dm-3 solution of Na2CO3 requires 20cm3 of  solution of HCl for neutralization. The concentration of the solution is",option:{a:"0.6 mol dm-3",b:"0.5 mol dm-3",c:"0.4 mol dm-3",d:"0.2 mol dm-3"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:104,question:"Chlorine gas is prepared in the laboratory by",option:{a:"Adding concentrated hydrochloric acid to solid manganese (IV) oxide",b:"Adding concentrated tetraoxosulphate (VI) acid to solid sodium chloride",c:"Dropping concentrated hydrochloric acid onto potassium tetraoxomanganate (VII) crystals",d:"Oxidizing concentrated hydrochloric acid using potassium heptaoxodichromate (VI) crystals"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"}],n={message:e,subject:o,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,n as default,e as message,t as status,o as subject,i as total};
